<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Cadaver: The Rotten Expansion</name>
    <directory>cadaver</directory>
    <id>2508822241</id>
    <description>Cadaver is a mod for The Binding of Isaac: Repentance that adds 11 new unlocks, a playable character, and their tainted counterpart! Explore the basement with Cadaver, Isaac's rotting corpse, and gain access to Golden Souls, Rotten Chests, and more!

[h1]CADAVER[/h1]
Cadaver only has one rotten eye, so he can only fire at a fixed 1.5 tears per second. All tear pickups are converted to an equivalent damage multiplier.

Cadaver can only obtain Rotten Hearts and Bone Hearts. Any red hearts that spawn are converted to Rotten Hearts, with a rare chance to convert into a Bone Heart.

Cadaver can pickup soul hearts, but they are immediately removed to spawn friendly critters!

Birthright turns all current and future blue flies into locusts!

Cadaver starts with Yuck Heart. Use it in combat or in Curse Rooms to hold on to your bone hearts.

[h1]CADAVER UNLOCKS[/h1]
[b]Vestments[/b] [i](Defeat Isaac and ??? as Cadaver)[/i]
[Angel Room] Gain a random Angel Room item effect in every room.

[b]Probiotics[/b] [i](Defeat Satan and The Lamb as Cadaver)[/i]
[Trinket] If Isaac has a Rotten Heart, gain a moderate stat boost.

[b]Soul of Cadaver[/b] [i](Defeat Hush as Cadaver)[/i]
Spawns friendly leeches, friendly maggots, a bone heart, and rotten hearts.

[b]Cadaver's Left Eye[/b] [i](Defeat Delirium as Cadaver)[/i]
[Treasure Room] Increased Damage. Fixes fire rate at 1.5 and converts all tear ups into an equivalent damage multiplier.

[b]Forbidden Fruit[/b] [i](Defeat Mother as Cadaver)[/i]
[Devil Room] When used, gain a permanent damage multiplier and tear delay reduction. Once used, Isaac takes periodic damage until the end of the run (persists through resurrections).

[b]Golden Soul[/b] [i](Defeat Beast as Cadaver)[/i]
Activates a random soul effect. Has a chance to spawn another Golden Soul upon use.

[b]Rotten Chests[/b] [i](Defeat Mega Satan as Cadaver)[/i]
Rarely, a normal chest will be replaced with a rotten variant that gives some additonal rotten-themed pickups. Also a chance to spawn a rotten pedestal item!

[h1]TAINTED CADAVER[/h1]
Tainted Cadaver fires at a fast, fixed tear rate. All tear pickups are converted to an equivalent damage multiplier.

Tainted Cadaver has 40% reduced damage.

Tainted Cadaver can only obtain [b]four[/b] Bone Hearts and fill them with Rotten Hearts. Any red hearts that spawn are converted to Rotten Hearts, with a chance to convert into a Bone Heart.

Tainted Cadaver can pickup soul hearts, but they are immediately removed to spawn friendly critters! Tainted Cadaver's friendly critters are [b]permanent[/b].

Tainted Cadaver starts with Halitosis. Using Halitosis will respawn any dead critters and will relocate all alive critters to Tainted Cadaver's location.

When Tainted Cadaver has Birthright, his friendly units automatically respawn after 3 seconds.

[h1]TAINTED CADAVER UNLOCKS[/h1]
[b]Halitosis[/b] [i](Defeat Hush and Delirium as Tainted Cadaver)[/i]
[Treasure Room] Active. Fire several large breath tears over 1 second. These tears pierce, apply poison and fear, and deal Isaac's tear damage.

[b]Morgue Key[/b] [i](Defeat Isaac, ???, Satan, The Lamb, and Mega Satan as Tainted Cadaver)[/i]
[Secret Room] Teleport to the Morgue. The Morgue includes a collection of pedestal items from the last completed run. Only one can be taken.

[b]Tech Drones[/b] [i](Defeat Mother as Tainted Cadaver)[/i]
[Treasure Room] Gain two familiar robots that orbit Isaac at a large distance. When Isaac fires tears, a tech laser connects the two bots.

[b]Hydrochloric Acid[/b] [i](Defeat Beast as Tainted Cadaver)[/i]
[Treasure Room] After hitting an enemy 5 times, all future attacks will deal additional flat damage.

[h1]MULTIPLAYER SUPPORT[/h1]
Item unlock progression is only tracked if Player 1 is Cadaver/Tainted Cadaver.

Morgue Key will only remember items held by Player 1.

Heart conversions to Rotten + Bone hearts are only done if Player 1 is Cadaver/Tainted Cadaver.

Multiple Tainted Cadavers share one army that respawns when any Tainted Cadaver uses Halitosis.


[h1]AUTHOR'S NOTE[/h1]
Thanks to everyone who has supported me during the development of this mod. This mod is content-complete and will not be receiving updates outside of bug-fixes and technical improvements.

Thanks to Carrygan for all of his testing support.

For full details, see the GitHub: https://github.com/Synthian/IsaacCadaver/blob/master/README.md</description>
    <version>2.3</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
</metadata>
